乔伊，这就是你爸妈叫你 不要跳上床的原因
Joe,that's why your parents told you not to jump on the bed!
本集播出：“果酱”
The One With the Jam
看看我，我在做果酱
Hey,look at me! I'm making jam!
我早上四点就起来了 那么早你怎么买得到水果？
-I've been at it since 4 a.m. -Where'd you get fruit at 4 a.m.?
在码头那儿买的 你一定不知道可以买到批发价
Down at the docks. You know,you can get it wholesale.
我根本不知道有码头
I didn't know there were docks.
手臂断了吗？
Is it broken?
不，但我得戴着这玩意儿 好几个礼拜
No,but I gotta wear this for a couple weeks.
你有没有告诉医生 你是因为跳上床才受伤？
You tell the doctor you did it jumping on your bed?
不，我编的故事本来有用的 但是…
No. I had a whole story worked out,but then...
钱德出卖了我
...Chandler sold me out.
抱歉，我想医生不会相信 你说的“手臂就自己脱落了”
I didn't think the doctor would buy that it "fell out of the socket."
这是什么？水果吗？
What is this? Fruit?
莫妮卡在做果酱
Monica's making jam.
我最爱果酱了！ 我们家怎么从来没有果酱？
Jam? I love jam! How come we never have jam at our place?
因为孩子们需要买新鞋
Because the kids need new shoes.
我得做正事了 我不想再为理查的事伤神
I'm going into business. I'm sick of being depressed about Richard.
我需要一个计划 来忘记我的男人
I needed a plan. A plan to get over my man.
什么事跟男人相反？ 就是果酱！
What's the opposite of man? Jam!
乔伊，不要！ 那个太烫了！
Joey,don't! It's way too hot!
那么这一份就算我的
This'll just be my batch.
到此为止
That's it.
喂，那个穿杰克鲁牌（美国服装名牌）的家伙
Hey,you,J. Crew guy....
你为何跟踪我？
Why are you following me?
这一周来，我往哪儿看都会看到你
All week,everywhere I look,there's you.
你也不回我电话 又把我的信退回来
You wouldn't return my calls. You sent back my letters.
再给我一次机会 拜托，乌苏拉
One more chance,Ursula. Please.
真是太尴尬了
This is awkward.
因为你要找的是乌苏拉 我是菲比，我们是双胞胎
Yeah,because you want Ursula,and I'm Phoebe. Twin sisters.
这是真的
Seriously.
太好了，我跟错人了
That's great. I'm stalking the wrong woman.
我真是个糊涂蛋！
I am such a dingus!
你不是糊涂蛋
Oh,you're not a dingus.
我只想让你知道 我不是总是这样的
I just want you to know I wasn't always like this.
在认识你姐姐之前 我只是卖手机的普通人
Before I met your sister,I was a normal guy who sold cellular phones.
听着，这不是你的错
Look,it's not your fault.
这就是她对待男人的方式
I mean,this is just what she does to guys,okay?
谢谢你
Well,thanks.
等等，我有个小故事告诉你
Wait. I got a little story.
我在念初中时 我以为自己是女巫
Once,in junior high school,I thought I was a witch.
有个辅导老师跟我说的话 我想可以帮助你
And a guidance counselor told me something that might help you.
他说“你根本不是女巫 你只是个普通学生”
He said,"Okay,you're not a witch. You're just an average student."
你懂我的意思吗？ 不太懂
-See what I'm saying? -Not really.
当我没说
Well,get over it.
你看起来是个好人
You seem like a really nice guy.
别对自己太苛刻，好吗？
Don't be so hard on yourself,okay?
没错，我想你是对的 谢谢你对我这么友善
You're right. I know you're right. And thanks for being so nice.
谢谢你
Thanks a lot.
你要不要去喝咖啡？
Want to get some coffee?
你不用走在我后面了
You don't have to walk behind me anymore.
“去买罐子，等会儿回来 莫妮卡盖勒”
"Gone for more jars. Be back later. Monica Geller."
等等，你看！
Wait a minute. Look!
整个房子里都没人
It's an empty apartment.
这间空房子里，只有我们两个
We're all alone in an empty apartment.
我在十分钟内得去上班
I have to be at work in 10 minutes.
好吧，我又不是年度最佳员工
All right. It's not like I'm employee of the year or anything.
在这里啊！
There it is!
这就是你要找的啊
Oh,that's what you mean.
我看起来很胖吗？
Do I look fat?
不会啊
No.
这点我可以接受
I accept that.
当珍妮丝问我时，我回答不 她却认为我说她像母牛
When Janice asked me and I said no,she thought I was calling her a cow.
重头再说一次给我们听…
Walk us through it,honey. Walk us through it.
珍妮丝说，她今天看起来胖吗 我看看她…
Janice said,"Hi. Do I look fat today?" And I looked at her
你看看她？
You looked at her?
你绝不能看
You never look.
你只能回答，就像反射动作 “我看起来胖吗？”，“不”
You just answer. It's like a reflex. "Do I look fat?" "No."
“她比我漂亮吗？”，“不”
"Is she prettier than I am?" "No."
“大小重要吗？”，“不”
"Does size matter?"
这点男女都适用
And it works both ways.
所以你们本来就知道这些？
So you both just know this stuff?
吵了大概三四十次后 你大概就记住了
After 30 or 40 fights,you kind of catch on.
好，比如说…
Okay. For instance:
珍妮丝旅行回来 她给你两种选择
Janice is coming back from a trip. She gives you two options.
选择一，她从机场 自己搭计程车回来
Option one: She'll take a cab home from the airport.
选择二，你在领行李的地方 与她碰面，你会怎么做？
Option two: You can meet her at baggage claim. What do you do?
简单，领行李的地方
Easy. Baggage claim.
错了，所以你是单身
Wrong! Now you're single.
其实是第三个秘密绝招
It's actually secret option number three.
你在登机门与她碰面 这就表现出你对她的爱
You meet her at the gate. That way she knows you love her.
好，这样真不错
Okay,this is good.
好，我有一个问题 珍妮丝晚上喜欢抱抱…
All right,I have one. Janice likes to cuddle...
我当然也喜欢抱抱
...at night,which I'm all for.
不过当你想睡觉时 你会想要一点空间
But when you want to go to sleep,you want some space.
我要怎样告诉她，才不会…
So how do I tell her that without...
不小心又说她胖之类的？
...you know,accidentally calling her fat or something?
抱歉，我们帮不了你 因为我们都是抱着睡的
Sorry,honey. We can't help you there,because we're cuddly sleepers.
我上班要迟到了
I'm late for work.
你们要不要下来？ 好，等一下就去
-Are you guys coming down? -Yeah. I'm right behind you.
祝你好运，钱德
Good luck,Chandler.
-谢谢瑞秋 -再见亲爱的 -再见亲爱的
-Thank you.-Bye, sweetie.-Bye, honey.
关于睡觉那件事
The sleeping thing.
非常困难，但可以解决
Very tricky business,but solvable.
我以为你们都是“抱着睡觉”
I thought you were "cuddly sleepers."
不，不是抱着睡 不是我，只有她
No,not cuddly. Not me. Just her.
我跟你一样，我需要空间
I'm like you. I need the room.
好，到这儿来
Okay,come here.
好，现在你在床上
Okay. You're in bed.
我还是用垫子好了
I'll use the cushion.
好，你在床上 她在你旁边，抱着你
Okay. You're in bed. She's over on your side,cuddling.
现在，你等她逐渐睡着…
Now,you wait for her to drift off...
然后你抱住她…
...and then you hug her...
然后把她滚到床的另一边
...and roll her over to her side of the bed.
然后你…
And then you...
你就滚到旁边去
... roll away.
抱住她
Hug for her.
自己滚到旁边去
Roll for you.
就像以前的“拥抱与翻滚”
The old "hug and roll."
只有一个问题 你把枕头当作女生，对吧？
One question. You're pretending the pillow's a girl,right?
记得小时候 你妈会把你送到电影院…
Remember when you were a kid,your mom would send you to the movies...
给你一罐果酱 和一根小汤匙？
...with a jar of jam and a little spoon?
你真漂亮
You're so pretty.
你知道那个跟踪我的人吗？ 我今天跟他说话了
You know that guy who's been following me? I talked to him today.
你跟他说话？你疯了吗？
You talked to him? Are you crazy?
第一，我没有疯 第二，用说的，别用喷的
First,I'm not crazy. And second,say it,don't spray it.
反正他叫做麦尔康 他也不是在跟踪我
Anyway,his name is Malcolm,and he wasn't following me.
我是说，他在跟踪没错 但他以为我是乌苏拉
I mean,he was,but he thought I was Ursula.
所以他不敢上前来跟我说话
That's why he couldn't just come up and talk to me.
因为有禁制令
Because of the restraining order.
我还是对麦尔康没有好感
Not feeling better about Malcolm.
不，他不是疯子
No,no,he's not a kook.
他只是个非常热情 极度浪漫的家伙…
He's just this very passionate,incredibly romantic guy...
只是有点过火了
...that just got a teensy bit carried away.
我们处得很好，而且他很可爱
We get along really well,and he's so cute.
天啊，你竟然对跟踪你姐姐的人有感觉
Oh,my God! You've got a crush on your sister's stalker.
我要帮他忘记乌苏拉的一切
I'm going to help him get "de-Ursula-ized."
就像乔伊跟她约会后 我为他做的一样
Like I did for Joey after he went out with her.
我没有跟踪她
I didn't stalk her.
我是问新闻 不是问天气
I asked for the news,not the weather.
乔伊，这是你的 这是黑莓红醋粟酱
Joey,this is for you. It's blackberry currant.
乔伊，我得问你
Joe,I got to ask.
影印店的那个女孩，全裸
The girl from the xerox place,buck naked...
还是你要一大缸果酱？
...or a big tub of jam?
你把两只手放在一起吧
Put your hands together.
你慢慢吃啊，那是最后一批
Take your time with that. It's my last batch.
没有果酱了？
No more jam?
你的果酱计划呢？
What happened to your jam plan?
我算过了 我每罐得卖17元才能赚回来
I figured out I'd need to charge $17 a jar just to break even.
所以我有个新计划 就是生小孩
So I've got a new plan now. Babies.
那你可能需要很大的罐子
Well,you'll need much bigger jars.
你们在谈什么？ 谈我要生孩子的事
-What are you talking about? -About me having a baby.
你是认真的吗？ 是啊
-Are you serious? -Yeah.
果酱计划让我开始 掌握自己的生活
The jam plan helped me take control of my life.
所以我就想 什么事对我最重要？
So I thought,"What is the most important thing to me?"
因此我就想出 生小孩这个计划
And that's when I came up with the baby plan.
你是不是忘了什么？
Aren't you forgetting something?
那个家伙叫什么？ 叫“爸爸”！
What is that guy's name? Dad!
我花了28年，找到一个 想与他共度终身的男人
It took me 28 years to find a man I wanted to spend my life with.
如果我还得再等28年 我就得56岁才生小孩
If I have to wait another 28 years,I'll be 56 before I can have a baby.
那样实在太愚蠢了
And that's just stupid.
那样叫愚蠢？
That's what's stupid?
我不需要一个真正的男人 只要他几只会游泳的小家伙
I don't need an actual man. Just a few of his best swimmers.
而且你可以在某个地方 得到那些小家伙
And there are places you can go to get that...stuff.
又要去码头了吗？
Down to the docks again?
晚安，宾宝贝
Night-night,Bing-a-ling.
晚安…
Night-night...
珍妮丝
...Janice.
看看她那一边的位置！
Look at all the room on her side!
都可以放一只大企鹅了
A giant penguin could fit over there.
不过那样会很奇怪
That'd be weird,though.
要开始“拥抱与翻滚”了
Hug and roll time.
我正在拥抱…
I'm hugging. I'm hugging.
你在翻滚，然后…
You're rolling,and....
太好了，自由了！
Yes! Freedom!
除了这只手臂以外！
Except for this arm!
我被困住了，手臂卡住了
I'm stuck. Stuck arm.
该玩以前那种桌布游戏了，一个快动作
Time for the old tablecloth trick. One fluid motion.
像猫一样矫捷…
Quick like a cat.
一、二…
And one,two...
三！
... three!
这是我的双眼望远镜
Here's my binoculars.
很好，你做得很好
Oh,great. You're doing great.
很不错，继续吧
Going strong. IKeep going.
这是我的夜视镜
These are my night-vision goggles.
这是我在公园里看她时 假装阅读的书
This is the book I pretend to read when I'm watching her in the park.
这些是填词游戏 只是打发时间用的
And these are Madlibs. They're just for fun.
这是我写的日志 记录她的一举一动
This is the log I kept,recording her every movement.
你要不要听听看？
Want to hear some of it?
我一点也不想听
Not even a little bit.
是跟你有关的
It's about you.
那好吧
Okay then.
我今天遇到菲比
"l met Phoebe today.
她对我很好 即使我真的是个败类
She was really nice to me even though I'm such a loser.
当我走回家时，我不断想着她
And when I was walking home,I thought about her a lot.
虽然很怪，却是很棒的感觉
It was weird,but kind of cool."
很好
Good.
你在想什么？
So what were you thinking?
我在想亲你是什么感觉？
I was thinking what it'd be like to kiss you.
真的吗？ 不
-Really? -No.
那只是我故意说的 这样我才能亲你
That's just something I said now so that maybe I could kiss you.
好啊
Oh,okay.
不，不用了 我刚吃了一罐芥末
No,it's all right. I just had a jar of mustard.
好，捐精者编号03815 来！
Okay. Sperm donor number 03815,come on down!
好，他是6尺2寸，170磅
Okay,he's 6'2",170 pounds.
他形容自己是 男性的吉娜戴维丝（女影星）
He describes himself as a male Gina Davis.
你是说除了我们之外 还有别人？
You mean there's more than one of us?
你不能这样做，莫妮卡 如果你这么做，我会…
You can't do this,Mon. If you do this,I'll
你会怎样？ 我会告诉妈
-You'll what? -I'll tell Mom.
很抱歉，他是对的 我爱你，可是你真的疯了
I'm sorry,but he's right. I love you,but you're crazy.
为什么这样就叫疯了？
Why? Why is this crazy?
就算这不是理想方法… 这根本不是…
-So this isn't the ideal way -Oh,it's not
嘴巴在动，我还在讲话！
Lips moving. Still talking.
这样可能不太理想，但…
It may not be ideal,but...
我真的准备好了
... I'm so ready.
我看到班看着你的样子
I see the way Ben looks at you.
让我心好痛，你知道吗？
It makes me ache,you know?
你看看，果酱饼干！
Check it out! Jam crackers!
好吧，这个如何？
Okay. All right,how's this?
27岁，意大利裔美国人
Twenty-seven,ltalian-American guy.
他是个演员
He's an actor.
在皇后区出生
Born in Queens.
好大的家庭！ 有七个妹妹…
Wow! Big family. Seven sisters...
他是唯一的…男孩
...and he's the only... boy.
天啊，个人评论写着 纽约尼克队万岁！
Oh,my God! Under personal comments: "New York Knicks rule."
对啊，纽约尼克队万岁！
Yeah,the Knicks rule!
乔伊，这个是你！
Joey,this is you!
让我看看
Let me see.
对啊
Oh,right!
你去精子银行？
You went to a sperm bank?
就在我参加 纽约大学的性研究之后
Right after I did that sex study at NYU.
你记不记得你生日时 我送你的毛衣？
Remember that sweater I gave you?
那是你用这样赚来的？
That's how you bought it?
不，那是我捐精子那天穿的
No. That's what I was wearing when I donated.
我真惊讶他们那儿 还会有我的小家伙
I'm surprised there's any of my boys left.
那里竞争很激烈的 还有真正的火箭科学家呢
It is pretty competitive. There's an actual rocket scientist here.
或许我该叫他们 把我演的“我们的日子”放上去
Maybe I should have them put my Days of our Lives gig on here.
多增加点声势
Juice this up a little.
那个疯子如何了？
How's the maniac?
他真迷人，我们接吻了
He's yummy. We did a little kissing.
菲比，你在做什么？
Phoebe,what are you doing?
不，他不会再犯了 他为了我戒掉了
No,no. He's not into that anymore. He quit for me.
那家伙迷恋你姐姐 天晓得到底有多久了
This guy has been obsessed with your sister for God knows how long.
你不能就这样算了
You don't just give that up.
他把他的夜视镜 和一切东西都交给我了
He gave me his night-vision goggles and everything.
一个有夜视镜的人 他说的话你也敢信？
You're taking the word of a guy who has night-vision goggles?
他不再跟踪她了 你觉得他还在跟踪她吗？
He's not still following her. You think he's still following her?
快醒醒，感觉一下 什么叫禁制令吧
Wake up and smell the restraining order.
你说我该怎么办？
What should I do?
若你真的很喜欢他 应该相信他才是
If you really like this guy,you should just trust him.
谢谢你，莫妮卡
Thank you,Monica.
或者你该跟踪他，看他去哪里
Or you could follow him.
我也会这么做 忘了我刚说的吧
That's what I'd do. Forget mine.
天啊，发生什么事？
What happened?
钱德发神经，把我转一圈…
Crazy Chandler spun me...
然后推下床
...off the bed.
转圈圈啊，听起来很好玩
Wow! Spinning! Sounds like fun.
我倒希望
I wish.
他只是在试罗斯的 那套“拥抱与翻滚”
He was just trying Ross' "hug and roll" thing.
罗斯的什么？
Ross' what?
当他抱住你 把你滚到旁边，再…
Where he hugs you and then he rolls you away,and....
我的…天…啊！
Oh... my...God!
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我只是在找我的…
Oh,I was just here looking for my... my....
吃过的旧三明治…在这里！
Part of an old sandwich. Here it is!
你在跟踪我吗？
Were you following me?
可能吧
Perhaps.
是的，我很抱歉
Yes. I'm sorry.
我怕你仍然迷恋我姐姐
I was afraid you were still hung up on my sister.
所以你在监视我
So you spied on me.
我真不敢相信你不信任我
I can't believe you don't trust me.
你怎么会知道呢？ 我的双胞胎姐姐正好经过！
Well,what do you know? There goes my identical twin sister!
一直走着 跟我长得一模一样
Just walking along,looking like me.
这是个奇异的巧合 还是你早知道她会搭这班车？
Is this a freakish coincidence,or did you know she takes this train?
对不起…
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
我试着停止，但控制不了
I tried to stop,but I couldn't.
我真可悲
I'm so pathetic.
不，不是你的错，我也有错
No,it's not your fault. It's partly my fault.
是我要你断然戒除这个毛病
I made you quit cold turkey.
我不能再跟你约会了 因为你是，你知道的…
Well,I can't date you anymore because you're,you know....
哇！
Wow!
但我一定会帮你 忘了我姐姐，好吗？
But I will definitely help you get over my sister. Okay?
试着跟踪我一阵子，好吗？
Stalk me for a while,huh?
我就像乌苏拉的补丁
I'll be like an Ursula patch.
我不知道
I don't know.
你就…你看，我正在走路！
Just.... Look,I'm going!
来吧
Come on.
我遇到柱子了 我会往哪边走？
I'm on the pillar. Which way will I go?
你要去哪里？ 我要去银行
-Where you going? -To the bank.
精子银行还是一般的
Sperm or regular?
精子银行
Sperm.
你确定要做这件事？
You're really doing it?
是啊，我挑了一个男的 编号37135
Oh,yeah. I picked a guy. 37135.
听起来不错
Sounds nice.
的确，他有棕发和绿眼睛
He does. He's got brown hair and green eyes.
不是开玩笑吧？
No kidding?
我以为你会选金发的
I figured you'd have picked a blond.
真的吗？为什么？
Really? Why?
我总是想像你和一个 高大聪明的金发男子，叫…
I always pictured you with a tall,smart,blond guy with a name like...
“荷依”这样的名字
...Hoyt.
那是个名字，没错
It's a name. Yeah.
我看到你在一间很棒的 有泳池的大房子
I saw you in this great house with a big pool.
他是游泳选手吗？
Is he a swimmer?
他可是有那种身材的
He's got the body for it.
我喜欢
I like that.
什么？
What?
你们有个牌子写着…
You have a sign that says:
“我们不在你的厕所游泳 所以别在我们的池子尿尿”
"We don't swim in your toilet. Don't pee in our pool."
我们才不会有那种牌子
We don't have that sign.
你会有的 那是我送的礼物
You do! It was a gift from me.
然后你会有三个很棒的孩子
And you have three great kids.
两个女孩和一个男孩？
Two girls and a boy?
他们戴着救生圈 绕着泳池边跑
And they wear little water wings,and they run around on the deck.
然后荷依用毛巾围住他们三个
And Hoyt wraps a towel around all three of them.
当然
Sure.
但是，你知道 这样听起来也不错
But,you know,this way sounds good too.
是啊
Yeah.
这家伙是宇航员？
Wow! This guy's an astronaut?
这太棒了…
That would have been cool...
但不会维持多久
...for a day.
她五点才会回来
She'll be back at 5.
五
Five!
我打电话给精子银行
I called the sperm bank.
崔比亚尼的小家伙 一点儿也没卖出去
They haven't sold a single unit of Tribbiani.
没有人要我出产的
Nobody wants my product.
我不懂
I don't get it.
也许如果他们亲眼见到我的话
Maybe if they met me in person.
你沾到一点在…
You got a thing on your....
弄掉了吧？
Get it?
是啊
Yeah.
嗨
Hello.
钱德，我可以跟你谈一下吗？
Chan,can I talk to you for a second?
当然，什么事？
Sure. What's up?
这是一件关于男女之间的事
Just one additional relationship thought.
这件事你大概已经知道了
Something you're probably aware of.
女人会互相传话的
Women talk.